Dear sir:

Hi! Good evening.

As I understand that you are looking for a CEO / MD for one of your clients, I would like to offer my candidature for the same. Came back recently to Ahmedabad, India and was working as CEO - MeTL group in Tanzania, Africa . Am <u>industry agnostic</u> having worked in various industries like Food, Textiles, Management consulting, Engineering.

With a combination of working in manufacturing, management consulting and teaching as a visiting professor, I would be a suitable fit for CEO/MD level position, as I bring BICS to the table. If you are looking for one who would challenge the status quo and be able to bring different perspective (which is important for a CEO than the industry per se), then I would fit the bill.

Have been working for the past 20+ years at CXO levels (out of total 33 years of total experience - predominantly in Manufacturing in various industries & Management Consulting). Set up 2 integrated green-field projects right from scratch (Mafatlal Burlington in India and Atlantic Mills in Thailand) and ran the factories (a strong proponent & implementer of Lean) and companies successfully apart from turning around two other.

Traveled all over the world extensively for business and have experience of working abroad as well- in Bangladesh, Tanzania (Africa) and Thailand.

Am a visiting professor of Operations, Marketing and Strategy in MBA schools of Nirma University, Ahmedabad University, Entrepreneurship Development Institute of India etc., for the past 15 years.

Have become the youngest team leader at the age of 25 years (in NDDB), the youngest departmental head at 28 (in Soma Textiles of Somany Group), the youngest Unit Head at 34 (in Mafatlal Group), the youngest Business Head at 36 (in President Park Group, Thailand).

For your ready reference, am enclosing herewith my resume.

In case you need further details, pl. do not hesitate to let me know.

Looking forward to your call / mail, with best regards

A B Raju B.Tech(Mech), MBA (IRMA) CEO - MeTL group, Tanzania

Ex- Director, Anwar Group Bangladesh, Ex-CEO Oxford Ind., Ex-CMO Somany Group , Ex-COO President Park Group Thailand, Ex-GM Mafatlal Burlington (Indo-US JV)

+91 98790 94120

P.S.: Pl. acknowledge the receipt of this mail. Thanks

ATYAM BASAVA RAJU

(A B Raju)



Phone: +91 98790 94120
Email: atyamraju@gmail.com
abraju@hotmail.com

PROFILE HIGHLIGHTS

Engineer + MBA with 30+ years of experience with over 20+ years at CXO levels across industries - Food, Textiles, Management Consulting

Set up 2 green-field projects right from scratch, ran the factories, companies and turned around another 2 companies successfully

Hands-on experience in various business functions - Projects, Production & Operations, Quality, SCM, Sales & Marketing

Was the youngest team leader at the age of 25 years in NDDB, the youngest Departmental Manager at 28 in Somany Group, the youngest Unit Head at 34 in Mafatlals and the youngest CEO at 36 in President Park Group in Thailand

SKILL-SETS

Lean Management ,Turn Around strategy, Growth Strategy & Blue Ocean Strategy, Analytical, Communication & Convincing, Design Thinking, Systems Approach, Leadership, Management Consulting

WORK EXPERIENCE:	
CEO MeTL Group Tanzania (2020 – Present)	 Head of the largest textile company in Tanzania - US\$ 70 Million Increased production by 25% and first quality by 5% Turned around the company from loss making to Profit making
DIRECTOR Anwar Group Bangladesh (2018 - 2019)	 Head of Textile Business of Anwar Group – Spinning, Yarn Dyeing, Weaving & Processing (Dyeing & Printing) - US\$ 100 Mn Streamlined entire systems to create BICS for MIS across organization Achieved full potential by de-bottlenecking the processes – Increased production by 10% with the same infrastructure Set up entire Marketing Co-ordination and PPC systems to reduce late deliveries – On-times deliveries % increased by almost 100%
CEO Biz Trans Consulting (2007 – 2018)	 3 Verticals - Management Consulting, Business Coaching and Executive Training Given services to Raymond, Adani, Vadilal, Hameem Group Bangladesh, BSL Ltd., Sheela Woodbridge, Gamini Textiles, VBC Hydraulics, Thermotech, Siddhi Cement etc., MRO (Management Resource Outsourcing) services to Malibu Tech for 1.5 years
CEO Oxford Ind. (2007)	 Manufacturing & Marketing of Shirting & Bottom-wear fabrics Achieved the highest top line in the history of the company
CMO (2003-2007) Soma Textiles (Somany Group company)	 Integrated Textile company (Spinning, Weaving, Processing) – Shirting, Bottomwear, Denim Top line increased by 27% & Profits by 340% - absolute figures once again were the highest in the history of the company at that time
Innings 1 Manager – Technical Services (1992-1996)	 Joined as Executive Assistant to CGM and got promoted as Manager – Tech. services within 1.5 year Developed a proper Information system (MIS) for better decision making. In depth analysis of all contract jobs helped save 70% of the monthly bills. Was part of core team that successfully computerized the production information system
COO President Park Group, Thailand (2001-2003)	 Head of entire Textiles Business Turned around Polyester fabric division As a major initiative into exports, appointed agents in big garment centres like Turkey and Bangladesh for Denim. Initial phase of the Denim Project (from scratch) was completed well within budget and time.
UNIT HEAD Mafatlal Burlington (1996-2001)	 Integrated Denim fabric manufacturing facility with Spinning, Weaving & Processing Completed the green-field project in a record time within the budget as Project Manager. Increased EBIDTA from 22% to 38%. First quality increased to 98.4%. Exports to 89% by value. Increased profits by 650% within 2 years Joined as Project Manager then got promoted as Operations Manager with in 2 years and then once again within one year got promoted as Unit Head of entire Works at Navsari
Executive (P&E) National Dairy	 Successfully managed Dhara Rapeseed Oil Project as youngest ever Team head. Commissioned Asia's largest Solvent Extraction Plant (that time) & Modified Decarticating

Development Board	machine for enhanced results.
(NDDB), Anand (1989-1992)	 Developed cheaper alternative to Tetrapack for oil packaging.
	 Trained many officers and supervisors in edible oil technology

CAREER ACCOMP	LISHMENTS & CORE COMPETENCIES			
SALES &	 Anwar Textiles, Bangladesh – Increased turnover by 10% to US\$ 100 Mn 			
MARKETING	2. Oxford Ind. India – Achieved highest Sales turnover in the history of the company in 2007			
MANAGEMENT -	3. Soma Textiles – Increased profits by 340% and turnover by 27% in 3 years time by revamping the			
_	entire product portfolio and creating a new marketing strategy			
As Business Head / Unit	4. Mafatlal Burlington – Increased EBIDTA by 16%, and increased exports from 52% to 89%			
	5. Added new customers – both domestic and export in almost every company I worked for, apart from			
Head	retaining the existing using Ansoff's model			
	1. Set-up Mafatlal Burlington (an Indo-US JV) factory of US\$ 20 Million in 1996-97 in record time of 14			
PROJECT	months right from scratch as its Project Manager & Employee No. 1			
MANAGEMENT	2. As a Business Head of Textiles of President Park Group, Thailand set up entire Atlantic Mills			
	company along with its factory within time and budget in 2001-02			
	 Using principles of Lean Manufacturing have achieved the best production results in every company I 			
PRODUCTION	worked throughout my career – Increasing absolute production, quality and reducing costs and			
MANAGEMENT	wastes			
IVIANAGEIVIENT	2. Impressed by my achievements, Burlington America invited me to do a benchmarking studies of all			
	their plants in the world – India, US & Mexico			
	1. Expert in Quality Management Systems – from TQM, Kaizen, 5S to OEE, VSM and other OpEx			
	concepts			
QUALITY	2. Anwar Textiles – Clinical analysis helped us improve by almost 5% of first quality			
MANAGEMENT	3. Mafatlal Burlington - first quality improved by full 12% to reach 98.4% (one of the world best)			
	4. Soma Textiles – Entire quality systems have been set-up to improve upon the quality levels to an			
	extent where we could start meeting the requirements of big brands like Arrow, Van Heusen etc.,			
	1. Collaborating with vendors to scout for and develop new / alternate products and using principles of			
PURCHASE /	CPFR, Communities of Practice helped in saving huge amounts of money – chemicals to packaging			
SCM	materials			
MANAGEMENT	2. Could reduce inventories across value chain – At Anwar Textiles reduced Grey stocks from 30 Lakhs			
MANAGEMENT	yards to 7 Lakh yards, at Mafatlal Burlington finished goods reduced from 8 Lakhs to 60 thousands			
	etc.,			
INFORMATION	1. Implemented SAP in Soma Textiles as Project Sponsor.			
SYSTEMS	Developed entire fabric inventory management system in MS Access in Mafatlal Burlington			
ENGINEERING	1. Being an Engineer, optimum resource utilization of various utilities – electricity, steam, water etc.,			
	comes naturally for me			
	2. At Mafatlal Burlington got ISO 14000 certification also with clear-cut objectives of resource			
	conservation measures			
HUMAN	 Recruiting, indentifying and grooming talent are my forte 			
DECOLIDEEC	2. Constant amountate LID contains at Mafathal Double standard in our conditions and the contains at the contains			

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

RESOURCES

Visiting Professor of Marketing , Operations & Strategy areas @ MBA Schools of Ahmedabad University, Entrepreneurship Development Institute of India (EDII), Nirma University, Pandit Deendayal Energy University, KIIT University

2. Created complete HR systems at Mafatlal Burlington and improved in other places

Guest Professor / Keynote speaker at IMI, IIPH, GLS University, Nagpur University, Anna University, GATE Institute, AMA, CII etc.,

EXPOSURE ABROAD

- 1. Worked in Thailand for 2 years, in Bangladesh 1+ year and in Tanzania 1 Year
- 2. Travelled to Mexico, USA to Europe, Turkey to Singapore, China & Hong Kong many times for business

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS							
Degree	Year of Passing	Institute	Remarks				
PGDRM (MBA)	1989	Institute of Rural Management, Anand (IRMA)	One of the Premier Management Schools in India (71%)				
B.Tech (Mech)	1987	Sri Venkateswara University, Tirupati	Passed in First Class with Distinction (73.4%)				